You'll laugh. You'll cry. You'll hurl.
Wayne's World is a comedy, music film directed by Penelope Spheeris.
The adventures of two amiably aimless metal-head friends, Wayne and Garth.
From Wayne's basement, the pair broadcast a talk-show called
"Wayne's World" on local public access television.
The show comes to the attention of a sleazy network executive who wants to produce a big-budget version
of "Wayne's World"—and he also wants Wayne's girlfriend, a rock singer named Cassandra.
Wayne and Garth have to battle the executive not only
to save their show, but also Cassandra.
Wayne Campbell, played by Mike Myers.
Garth Algar, played by Dana Carvey.
Benjamin Kane, played by Rob Lowe.
Cassandra, played by Tia Carrere.
Stacy, played by Lara Flynn Boyle.
Dreamwoman, played by Donna Dixon.
Wayne's World is a 1992 American comedy film directed by Penelope Spheeris, produced by
Lorne Michaels, and written by Mike Myers and Bonnie and Terry Turner.
Based on the SNL sketch by Myers, it stars Myers in his feature film debut as Wayne Campbell and Dana Carvey as
Garth Algar, a pair of rock and heavy metal fans who broadcast a public-access television show.
It also features Tia Carrere, Rob Lowe, Lara Flynn Boyle and Brian Doyle-Murray in supporting roles, with
cameos by Chris Farley, Ed O'Neill, Ione Skye, Meat Loaf, Robert Patrick and Alice Cooper.
Wayne's World was released in the United States on
February 14, 1992, by Paramount Pictures.
A critical and commercial success, it was the tenth-highest-grossing film of 1992 and
remains the highest-grossing film based on a Saturday Night Live sketch.
A sequel, Wayne's World 2, was released the following year.
The film explores themes of romantic rivalry, heavy metal,
parody, singer, breaking the fourth wall.
The tone is lighthearted.